Guide to the Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1901-1977; Series II; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  - GERTRUDE STEIN - OUTGOING
    - Chapman, Elizabeth Fuller ("Bobsy"), 1934-46 (Box 9, Folder 106-110)
      Includes typescript statement by GS on Sir Francis Rose, 1934, letter from Francis Picabia to GS, 1935, and transcriptions by Carl Van Vechten
    - Coburn, Alvin Langdon, 1913-14 (Box 9, Folder 111)
      Includes transcript
    - Cone, Etta, 1922-24, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - Cook, William, 1934-46, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - Crawford, Dorothy, 1935 Feb 6 (Box 9, Folder 114)
      From ABT
    - Crowninshield, Frank, [1934?], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Douglas, Mrs., 1934 (Box 9, Folder 116)
      One letter from ABT
    - Draper, Muriel, [1925?] (Box 9, Folder 117)
      Also addressed to Max Ewing
    - Ehrman, Lillian May, 1935 Aug 7 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - Elkus, Charles De Young, Mrs., [1910 Jul 7?] (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Ewing, Max, 1925-33, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 120)
      See also: Muriel Draper, Box 9, folder 117
    - Fish, Marjorie E., 1934 Jun 23 (Box 9, Folder 121)
    - Fisher, Annie, [1925 May?] (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - Frank, Ellen [Ellen Bloom], 1935 (Box 9, Folder 123)
      Includes clipping about GS appearance at the University of Chicago, 1935 Mar 8
    - Gibb, Henry Phelan, 1913-36 (Box 9, Folder 124-125)
      Includes copy of letter from HPG to G. B. Shaw, 1931, from Brian Rhys to GS, 1934 May 20, and from Sylvia Meech to GS, 1934 May
    - Goodspeed, "Bobsy"
      See: Chapman, Elizabeth Fuller ("Bobsy"), Box 9, folder 106-110
    - Gorer, Geoffrey, [1926?] (Box 9, Folder 126)
    - Hasselriis, Mark, 1946 Jan 20 (Box 10, Folder 127)
      Includes printed copy of Petits poemes: Pour un livre de lecture inscribed to MH by GS and transcriptions of letters from MH to his family, 1945
    - Hubbell, Lindley Williams, 1928-41 (Box 10, Folder 128-129)
    - Hurd, Clement, 1939-40 (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - James, David, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 131)
    - Johnson, Lamont and Toni Merrill Johnson, 1945-46 (Box 10, Folder 132)
    - Keogh, Andrew
      See: Yale University Library, Box 12, folder 183
    - Knollenberg, Bernhard, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 133)
      Includes transcriptions of some letters
    - Levy, Harriet, [ca. 1910-28] (Box 10, Folder 134)
    - Loeb, Harold, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 135)
      Includes carbons of letters from HL to GS
    - Lutz, Mark, 1934-35 (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - Lynes, George Platt, 1925-34 (Box 10, Folder 136a)
    - Maurer, Alfred M. ("Alfy"), 1924 Mar 2 (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - Morris, G.L.K., [1932?-39?] (Box 10, Folder 138)
      One letter by ABT
    - Richards, Grant, 1911-14 (Box 10, Folder 139)
      Includes transcriptions
    - Rogers, William Garland, 1934-46 (Box 10, Folder 140-145)
      Includes typescript of La Baronne Pierlot
    - Sanders, F.J.M., 1927 Jan 13 (Box 10, Folder 146)
    - Sawyer, Julian, 1941, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 147)
      Includes transcriptions and manuscript fragment of Mrs. Reynolds by GS
    - Schiddel, Edmund, 1934 Apr 5 (Box 10, Folder 148)
    - Sears, William P., Jr., 1936-41 (Box 10, Folder 149-150)
      Includes holograph of poem William P. Sears, Jr. on letter of [1939 Oct?]
    - Staton, Harry P., [ca. 1934-35] (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - Stein, Julian and Rosellen, [1929]-45 (Box 11, Folder 152-153)
    - Steward, Samuel, 1933-45 (Box 11, Folder 154-155)
      Includes Why I Like Detective Stories, printed version from Harper's Bazaar, 1937 Nov
    - Sutherland, Donald, 1934-46 (Box 11, Folder 156)
      Includes note from DS explaining GS references to Katherine Anne Porter
    - Sweet, Clyde Robert, 1945-46 (Box 11, Folder 157)
      Includes notes about letters by CRS and letter of introduction for CRS to Marie Laurencin by GS
    - Tanner, Allen
      See: Pavel Tchelitchew, Box 11, folder 159a
    - Taylor, Ellen Alix DuPoy, [1929-45] (Box 11, Folder 158)
    - Taylor, Prentiss, 1935, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 159)
      Includes notes by PT and transcript of journal entry by PT and letter from PT to GS, 1935
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1926-31, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 159a)
      Includes letters also addressed to Allen Tanner
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1927-29 (Box 11, Folder 160-166)
    - Thomson, Virgil, 1929-46 (Box 12, Folder 167-176)
      Includes letter from Jo Davidson to GS, 1928 and from the BBC to GS, 1938
    - Weeks, Mabel Foote, 1901-[25?] (Box 12, Folder 177)
      (From GS and Leo Stein)
    - White, Max, 1934, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 178)
    - Whitehead, William, 1945-46 (Box 12, Folder 179)
    - Wilcox, Wendell, 1936-46 (Box 12, Folder 180-181)
    - Willis, Malcolm, 1936 Feb 8 (Box 12, Folder 182)
    - Yale University Library, 1937, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 183)
      Letter of 1937 Nov 23 is in the hand of Thornton Wilder with transcription and cover letter from TW, 1938 Feb 2
    - Unidentified (photocopy), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 184)
  - GERTRUDE STEIN - INCOMING
    - BBC [British Broadcasting Corporation], 1938
      See: GERTRUDE STEIN - OUTGOING, Virgil Thomson, Box 12, folder 175
    - Davidson, Jo, 1928
      See: GERTRUDE STEIN - OUTGOING, Virgil Thomson, Box 11, folder 163
    - Gorer, Geoffrey, 1926 Nov 20 (Box 12, Folder 185)
    - Meech, Sylvia, 1934 May
      See: GERTRUDE STEIN - OUTGOING, Henry Phelan Gibb, Box 9, folder 125
    - Picabia, Francis, 1935
      See: GERTRUDE STEIN - OUTGOING, Elizabeth Fuller ("Bobsy") Chapman, Box 9, folder 107
    - Picasso, Pablo, [1910 Aug?] (Box 12, Folder 186)
      with note from Jacob Moses to Richard Moses
    - Rhys, Brian, 1934 May 20
  - ALICE B. TOKLAS - OUTGOING
    - Brewer, Joseph, 1955-58 (Box 12, Folder 187)
    - Campbell, Sandy and Donald Windham, 1961-66 (Box 12, Folder 188-189)
    - Clifford, William, 1947-48 (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - Cook, William and Jeanne, 1946-55 (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - Dana, Richard, 1948 Mar 3 (Box 12, Folder 192)
    - [Daniel-Rops, Mr. and Mrs.], 1947 Aug 29 (Box 13, Folder 193)
      Includes note about letter by Joan Chapman
    - Davidson, Alexander, Jr., 1951 Feb 27 (Box 13, Folder 194)
    - [Ericsson, Paul], 1955 Nov 6 (Box 13, Folder 195)
    - Fourcade, Xavier and Eugene Taylor, 1957-62 (Box 13, Folder 196-97)
    - Hansen, Agnes Camilla and Elizabeth Hansen ["Lilyana"], 1926?, 1947-63 (Box 13, Folder 198)
      Includes notes by EH
    - Hubbell, Lindley Williams, 1950 Jan 1 (Box 13, Folder 199)
    - Jackson, David, 1961 May 25 (Box 13, Folder 200)
    - Knapik, Harold and Virginia, 1950-65, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 201-206)
    - Levy, Harriet, 1946, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 207)
    - Loos, Anita, 1963, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 208)
      Includes envelope dated 1957 (from ABT to AL)
    - Lutz, Mark, 1946-63 (Box 13, Folder 209)
    - Merrill, James, 1953-64 (Box 13, Folder 210)
    - Plummer, Hellen, 1951 Dec 30 (Box 13, Folder 211)
    - Rambo, Christopher (photocopy), 1948 Jun 30 (Box 13, Folder 212)
      Includes 2 photographs: Annette Rosenshine, 1897 and ABT and Harriet Levy, 1909
    - Raney, William, 1948 Jun 2
      See: William Garland Rogers, Box 13, folder 213
    - Rogers, William Garland and Mildred Weston Rogers, 1947-[62] (Box 13, Folder 213-214)
      Includes letter from ABT to William Raney forwarded to WGR, 1948 Jun 2
    - Rosenshine, Annette (photostat), 1957 Jan 16 (Box 14, Folder 215)
    - Sutherland, Donald and Gilberte, 1947-67 (Box 14, Folder 216-220)
    - Taylor, Ellen Alix DuPoy, 1946-51 (Box 14, Folder 221)
    - Taylor, Prentiss, 1946 Nov 4 (Box 14, Folder 222)
      with transcription and note by PT
    - Taylor, Eugene
      See: Xavier Fourcade, Box 13, folder 196
    - Weeks, Mabel, 1946 Aug 22 (Box 14, Folder 223)
    - Windham, Donald
      See: Sandy Campbell, Box 12, folder 188
    - Whitehead, Mr. and Mrs. William, 1945-66 (Box 14, Folder 224-225)
  - THIRD-PARTY
    - Barry, Joseph, to Harper's Magazine, 1947-48 (Box 14, Folder 226)
      Includes response from Harper's
    - Beauvoir, Simone de, to Edward Burns, 1977 Mar 31 (Box 14, Folder 227)
    - Berman, Eugene, to James R. Mellow, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 228)
    - Clark, Dorothy S., to Harriet, 1934 Mar 24 (Box 14, Folder 229)
    - Flanner, Janet, to Edward Burns, 1973 Jan 28 (Box 14, Folder 230)
    - Gallup, Donald, to Geoffrey Gorer, 1952 Sep 4 (Box 14, Folder 231)
    - Haas, Robert, to William P. Sears, Jr., 1940, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 232)
    - Hellman, Lillian, to Edward Burns, 1977 Apr 5 (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - Macdonald-Wright, Stanton, to James Mellow, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 234)
    - Poe, Edgar Allen [lawyer], to Porter and Porter [Law firm], 1958, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 235)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, to Joseph Barry, 1948 Jun 17 (Box 14, Folder 236)
    - Rohan, Dilkusha, to Mr. Jeffries, 1963 Nov 6 (Box 14, Folder 237)
    - Thomson, Virgil, to William P. Sears, Jr., 1944 Jan 31 (Box 14, Folder 238)
    - Trampert, Lucette and Pierre Demarne, to Unknown (wedding invitation), [1952] (Box 14, Folder 239)
    - Ullman, Eugene P. - Open letter to Julian Sawyer, 1948 May 20 (Box 14, Folder 240)
      Includes on verso a typescript of Moral Tales of 1920 and 1921
    - White, Max, to Liveright (Publisher), draft (photocopy), 1974 Nov (Box 14, Folder 241)
      Includes explanatory note addressed to Donald Gallup
    - Unidentified correspondents (Box 14, Folder 242)
- Other Papers, 1919-1985; Series III; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  Series III, Other Papers, is arranged alphabetically by name of donor or source.
  - ADATO, PERRY MILLER
    - Transcripts of filmed interviews for NET program on Gertrude Stein [incomplete], 1970 (Box 15, Folder 243-244)
      Includes: Virgil Thomson, Janet Flanner, Maurice Grosser, Jacques Lipchitz, Pierre Balmain and Joseph Barry
  - ATLANTIC MONTHLY FILES
    - Correspondence with and about Gertrude Stein, some enclosing manuscripts of writings by GS, 1919-42 (Box 15, Folder 245-249)
      Correspondents include: Ellery Sedwick, Bennett Cerf, Ted Weeks, Chester Kerr, Margot Johnson, William Bradley, Joseph Barber, Jr., J. Connolly, A. Mervyn Davies and Alfred Harcourt.
      Includes drafts of several letters by GS
      Enclosed manuscripts include: Ireland [Typescript carbon, 1919], The Revery of the Zionist [Typescript carbon, 1919], Cezanne [Typescript carbon, 1927], What Does She See When She Shuts Her Eyes [Typescript, corrected, n.d.]
    - Readers' comments on Gertrude Stein, 1925-34, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 250)
      Includes letter from B.F. Skinner [1934 Feb 8], carbon of letter from Edward Aswell to Alden James [1934 Sep], carbon of letter from Alden James to Edward Aswell [1934 Sep], and letter from Joseph Jastrow [1934]
  - BANKS, RICHARD
    - Musical settings of works by Gertrude Stein: Songs From the First Reader, Sonnets That Please, and Subject- Cases, sheet music, holograph mimeograph, [1953]-54 (Box 16, Folder 251)
  - BARLOW, SAMUEL LATHAM
    - "Ave Dione: A Tribute," drafts, typescript and carbon, corrected (Box 16, Folder 252)
  - BARNEY, NATALIE CLIFFORD
    - Foreword to As Fine as Melanctha [Yale Edition, 1954], typescript carbon, corrected [2 copies] (Box 16, Folder 253)
  - BERMAN, EUGENE
    - Program and postcards for exhibition, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 254)
  - BYRNSIDE, RONALD
    - "The Garden," [cantata score], photocopy, corrected, 1959
      See: Oversize, Box 39, folder 635
  - COLE, NANCY
    - "Gertrude Stein's Gertrude Stein" BBC broadcast, script, mimeograph, corrected, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 255)
  - CONRAD, DODA
    [Files concerning fund for Alice B. Toklas]
    - Correspondence
      - Azam, D. A., 1965, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 256)
      - Burns, Edward, 1969-76 (Box 16, Folder 257)
      - Barry, Joseph, 1965 Jan 26 (Box 16, Folder 258)
      - Chapman, Elizabeth Fuller ("Bobsy"), 1964-65 (Box 16, Folder 259)
      - Flanner, Janet, 1964-67, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 260)
      - Harrison, Gilbert, 1966 Aug (Box 16, Folder 261)
      - Kahnweiler, Daniel-Henry, 1964 Sep (Box 16, Folder 262)
      - Picasso, Jacqueline, 1964 Sep 9 (Box 16, Folder 263)
      - Sutherland, Donald, 1968 Mar 17 (Box 16, Folder 264)
      - Taylor, Redvers, 1966, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 265)
      - Thomson, Virgil, 1964-66 (Box 16, Folder 266)
      - Toklas, Alice, 1959-63, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 267)
        To Doda Conrad and Marya Freund
      - Wilder, Isabel, 1965, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 268)
      - Wilder, Thornton, 1965, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 269)
      - Winant, Francine, 1965 Jan 15 (Box 16, Folder 270)
    - Legal and literary correspondence, 1964-75 (Box 16, Folder 271-274)
    - Wills, 1948, 1961, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 275)
    - Financial papers, 1964-69 (Box 16, Folder 276-278)
    - Clippings, 1963-69 (Box 16, Folder 279)
  - COX, KENYON
    - "The 'Modern' Spirit in Art," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 280)
  - DYDO, ULLA
    - Research material gathered concerning Gertrude Stein at the Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, MA, 1893, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 281)
      Includes photocopies of photographs of GS, photocopy of directory of students, and photocopy of letter to UD from Marine Biological Laboratory, 1983 Nov 4
  - FIG, JOHNNY
    - "A Rose is a Rose," sheet music, photocopy, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 282)
  - HARRISON, GILBERT A.
    - 90th birthday book of Alice B. Toklas, 1967
      See: Oversize. Box 39, folder 636
      mixed media - bound volume (in full blue leather) including photographs of ABT, members of her family, and apartment at 5 rue Christine. Decorated by Robert Osborn, with calligraphy by John Malcolm Brinnin. ABT died before the book could be presented to her.
  - KATZ, LEON
    - Transcriptions of Gertrude Stein's studies for The Making of Americans, typescript photocopies, corrected, [1979] (Box 17, Folder 283-290)
  - LACHMAN, ARTHUR
    - "Gertrude Stein as I Knew Her", typescript, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 291)
  - MARTIN, VERNON
    - "Ladies' Voices, a dramatic opera," [score], photocopy, corrected, 1955
      See: Oversize, Box 39, folder 637
  - PADGETTE, PAUL
    - Introduction to exhibit of Stein material prepared by Padgette, typescript mimeograph (with photocopies of clippings and an invitation), 1964 (Box 17, Folder 292)
      See also: Series IV, Photographs - exhibitions, Box 19, folders 326-327, and Series IX. Film and Sound Recordings
    - Letters to the editor of California Living, photocopy, with copy of printed letter, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 293)
  - PIVANO, FERNANDA DI
    - "Gertrude Stein, Pionera di un Secolo," galley proof (from Il Pensiero Critico ), 1952 Mar (Box 17, Folder 293a)
    - "Introduzione a uno studio su Gertrude Stein," typescript carbon, corrected, galley proof and printed version (in La Rassegna d'Italia ), 1948 (Box 17, Folder 294)
  - REED, JOSEPH
    - "A Gertrude Stein Alphabet," photograph of one section, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 295)
  - ROGERS, WILLIAM GARLAND
    - When This You See Remember Me, setting typescript, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 296-299)
  - ROHAN, DILKUSHA
    - Holograph notes for "The Last Time I Saw Alice" and for a biography of Con Markiewicz and other writings (Box 18, Folder 300)
      Includes letter from Lori Masterson to Edward Burns, [1979] Jan 18
  - ROREM, NED
    - Musical setting of "I am Rose," holograph and printed version (2 copies), 1955, [1963] (Box 18, Folder 301)
    - Broadside - facsimile of holograph page of "I am Rose", 1955 Sep 29
      See: Oversize, Box 39, folder 638
  - SAWYER, JULIAN
    - Directions for a one-man, surréaliste production of "Four Saints in Three Acts," typescript, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 301a)
      Includes: Letter from JS to Norman Holmes Pearson, 1940
  - SCHOOL FOR THE PERFORMING ARTS, AMSTERDAM - MIME DEPARTMENT
    - "Yes is for a Very Young Man" performance videotape, 1985 (Box film, Folder 302)
      Video-bcn (1-inch) tape of performance directed by Tom Jansen and Wilbert Bank, produced by Paul Arthur van Dijk. Accompanied by booklet of descriptive material
  - SIMON, LINDA
    - Research files on Gertrude Stein's American tour, 1934-35, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 303-305)
      Includes letters from various libraries, most accompanied by photocopies of articles; loose photocopies of articles; and letters from Tess Croger and Frederick Hand concerning their memories of GS
  - SPRIGGE, ELIZABETH
    - "Journal in search of Gertrude Stein," TS carbon, corrected, [1954-55?] (Box 18, Folder 306-307)
  - STEIGER, ROBERT
    - Pages from a diary recording visit by GS and ABT to a gallery, [1935?] (Box 18, Folder 308)
  - SUTHERLAND, DONALD
    - "The Meaning of Poetry Now," offprint, [1952] (Box 18, Folder 309)
    - The Writing of Gertrude Stein, typescript carbon, corrected by ABT, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 310)
      Includes letter from Donald Sutherland to ABT, 1956 Jun 8
  - THOMSON, VIRGIL
    - Preface to Bee Time Vine [Yale Edition, 1953], typescript, corrected (Box 18, Folder 311)
  - TOKLAS, ALICE B.
    - Will - 2 versions, photocopies, 1959, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 312)
  - VAN VECHTEN, CARL
    - Gertrude Stein memorial program, New York, May 22, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 313)
      Includes drafts of comments by CVV, drafts of notes about GS by CVV (dating from 1914), typescript fragment The Mother of Us All, annotated, statement about GS by Lise DeHarme, short bibliography on GS and autographed program
    - Introduction to "Last Operas and Plays", notes, typescript and holograph (Box 18, Folder 313a)
  - THE WIDENING CIRCLE
    - Bibliographic records for special issue on Gertrude Stein, Fall 1973, 1972-74 (Box 18, Folder 314)
      Includes correspondence with contributors, photocopy of mock-up of proof pages, corrected, and printed version
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - "Slide-drums and slide-trombones," typescript carbon (Box 18, Folder 315)
    - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 18, Folder 316)
    - Map of Père Lachaise cemetery with location of Gertrude Stein's grave marked, [1948] (Box 18, Folder 317)
- Photographs, 1918-1976; Series IV; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Series IV, Photographs, is divided into four sections.
  - PEOPLE AND PLACES
    - Stein, Gertrude, ca. 1918-46 (Box 19, Folder 318)
      Includes shot of Stein taken by George Platt Lynes, 1928
    - Toklas, Alice B., 1948-76 (Box 19, Folder 319)
      Includes painting of ABT, 1976
    - Thomson, Virgil, ca. 1925 (Box 19, Folder 320)
    - Snapshots taken by Addison Metcalf, 1939, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 321)
      Includes shots of ABT and Basket and scrap of paper [written on by Stein?]
    - Grave of Gertrude Stein in Père Lachaise cemetery, Paris, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 322)
    - 27 rue de fleur, undated
  - ARTWORK
    - Prints of photographs of artwork owned by, or featuring GS, and prints of artwork used in exhibition at the Yale University Art Gallery (Box 19, Folder 323-325)
  - EXHIBITIONS
    - Views including: Bookstore windows, Addison Metcalf collection, and UC-Berkeley exhibition, 1946-74 (Box 19, Folder 326-327)
      See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 639
  - PRODUCTIONS OF STEIN WORKS
    - Brewsie and Willie, Touring Players photographed by Carl Van Vechten, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 328)
    - Faust an opera or Dr. Faustus Lights the Lights, Beaver College, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 329)
    - Faust an opera or Dr. Faustus Lights the Lights, Living Theatre photographed by Carl Van Vechten, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 330)
    - Faust an opera or Dr. Faustus Lights the Lights, Playhouse Repertory Company, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 331)
    - Four Saints in Three Acts [Marquee at Broadway Theatre] photographed by Carl Van Vechten, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 332)
    - Ladies Voices, Living Theatre, photographed by Carl Van Vechten, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 333)
    - The Mother of Us All, Brandes Matthews Theatre photographed by Carl Van Vechten, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 334-337)
    - What Happened, Randall Playhouse, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 338)
    - "When This You See, Remember Me", 1959 (Box 20, Folder 339)
    - Yes is For A Very Young Man, Princeton University, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 340-342)
    - Yes is For A Very Young Man, Interplayers (some photographs by Carl Van Vechten), 1951 (Box 20, Folder 343)
    - Yes is For A Very Young Man, Northwestern University, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 344)
    - Yes is For A Very Young Man, Purdue Playhouse, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 345)
    - Yes is For A Very Young Man, London production (Box 20, Folder 346)
- Pre-1946 Printed Material, 1934-1942; Series V; 0.25; (1 box)
  Series V, Pre-1946 Printed Material, is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Announcement of publication of Gertrude Stein bibliography by Yale University Library, [1941] (Box 21, Folder 347)
  - Bibliography of Gertrude Stein: Gotham Book Mart, typescript carbon, [1935?] (Box 21, Folder 348)
  - Book catalogues listing Stein material, 1934-39 (Box 21, Folder 349)
  - Exhibition catalog: Wilfredo Lam, Pierre Matisse Gallery, 1942 Nov 17 (Box 21, Folder 350)
  - Gertrude Stein number of the Academic Observer of the Utica Free Academy, 1937 Feb (Box 21, Folder 351)
  - Invitation to a lecture by Gertrude Stein: Plays and What They Are, New York City, [1934] Oct 30 (Box 21, Folder 352)
  - Invitation to a lecture by Gertrude Stein: Columbia University Library, 1935 Apr 24 (Box 21, Folder 353)
  - Invitation to a lecture by Gertrude Stein, with Ticket: Richmond Academy of Arts, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 354)
  - News release from Harcourt and Brace quoting letters from Gertrude Stein, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 355)
  - Note from "d" to "brother" found in second-hand copy of Four Saints in Three Acts, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 356)
- Post-1946 Printed Material, 1920-1987; Series VI; 5; (12 boxes)
  Series VI, Printed material post-1946, is arranged alphabetically by name or type of material, with clippings appearing first.
  - About Gertrude Stein
    - General clippings, 1946-84, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 357-367)
      See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 640
    - Stein and Art, 1945-68, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 368)
    - Critical and Biographical, 1946-84, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 369-375)
      See also: Oversize, Box 39, folder 641
    - Cartoons and caricatures, 1976-77 (Box 23, Folder 376)
    - Pictures, 1949-62, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 377)
  - Family and Friends
    - Alfred, William, 1966 Jan 12 (Box 24, Folder 378)
    - Balmain, Pierre, 1952 Feb 8 (Box 24, Folder 379)
    - Barney, Natalie, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 380)
    - Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1953 Dec (Box 24, Folder 381)
    - Barry, Joseph, 1972 Feb (Box 24, Folder 382)
    - Bérard, Christian, 1949 May 9 (Box 24, Folder 383)
    - Berners, Gerald, Lord, 1950 Apr 21 (Box 24, Folder 384)
    - Bradley, Jenny Bradley, William, 1960 Dec 11 (Box 24, Folder 385)
    - Caruso, Dorothy Mrs., 1955 Dec 17 (Box 24, Folder 386)
    - Cone, Claribel Cone, Etta Cone, Frederic W., 1949-63, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 387)
    - Davidson, Jo, 1920-80, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 388-389)
    - Dufy, Raoul, 1953 Mar 24 (Box 24, Folder 390)
    - Duncan, Raymond, 1966 Aug 17 (Box 24, Folder 391)
    - Faÿ, Bernard, 1951 Oct 3 (Box 24, Folder 392)
    - Ferren, John, 1970 Jul 26 (Box 24, Folder 393)
    - Flanner, Janet, 1978 Nov 8 (Box 24, Folder 394)
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1971 Mar 26 (Box 24, Folder 395)
    - Gallatin, A.E., 1952 Jun 17 (Box 24, Folder 396)
    - Gannet, Lewis, 1966 Feb 5 (Box 24, Folder 397)
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John, 1957 Sep 23 (Box 24, Folder 398)
    - Halsey, Sibyl (Lady Colefax), 1950 Sep 27 (Box 24, Folder 399)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins Mrs., 1951 Dec 3 (Box 24, Folder 400)
    - Harriman, Marie Norton Mrs., 1970 Sep 27 (Box 24, Folder 401)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1933-66 (Box 24, Folder 402)
    - Hockaday, Ela, 1956 Mar 28 (Box 24, Folder 403)
    - Kahnweiler, Daniel-Henry II, 1979 Jan 13 (Box 24, Folder 404)
    - Kohn, Estelle, 1955 Nov 7 (Box 24, Folder 405)
    - Korzybska, Mira Edgerly, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 406)
    - Lambert, Constant, 1951 Aug 22 (Box 24, Folder 407)